<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ysocialtwin.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ysocialtwin.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-21T11:44:49+01:00</updated><id>https://ysocialtwin.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Y Social</title><subtitle>Y Social is a cutting-edge Digital Twin of a microblogging platform. It enables realistic social media simulations by integrating Large Language Models (LLMs) agents. Describe your desired scenario - be it a political community, a mental health support group or a sportive fandom - and observe complex social behaviours emerge.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">(Here) We are Y!</title><link href="https://ysocialtwin.github.io/blog/2024/intro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="(Here) We are Y!" /><published>2024-08-01T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-08-01T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://ysocialtwin.github.io/blog/2024/intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ysocialtwin.github.io/blog/2024/intro/"><![CDATA[<p>Imagine a virtual world where you can simulate and analyze the intricate dynamics of social media platforms. Picture a digital space that mimics real-life interactions, allowing researchers to experiment and learn without the constraints and unpredictability of the real world. Welcome to the era of digital twins—specifically, a groundbreaking project called Y.</p>

<p>Y is a digital twin of an Online Social Media platform that takes advantage of cutting-edge artificial intelligence, particularly large language models (LLMs), to create interacting agents that mimic real user behavior.</p>

<p>Think of Y as a sophisticated mirror of social media, where every like, share, and tweet can be explored in a controlled environment.</p>

<h5 id="what-is-a-digital-twin">What is a “Digital Twin”?</h5>

<p>Digital twins are virtual replicas of physical systems, allowing for detailed analysis and experimentation.</p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/dt.jpg" style="width: 700px;" /></p>

<p>In the realm of social media, digital twins like Y open up new possibilities for understanding complex online interactions.
By providing a safe space to explore how users interact, share information, and influence one another, Y offers researchers a unique opportunity to uncover the hidden dynamics that drive our digital lives.</p>

<h5 id="harnessing-the-power-of-llms">Harnessing the Power of LLMs</h5>

<p>At the heart of Y are large language models, the same technology that powers advanced AI systems like ChatGPT.</p>

<p>These models allow Y to generate realistic text content and predict user responses, making the virtual interactions within Y remarkably lifelike. 
By simulating how users might engage with content, Y provides insights into user behavior, the spread of information, and the potential impact of different platform policies.</p>

<h5 id="why-it-matters">Why It Matters?</h5>

<p>The implications of Y’s capabilities are vast. 
Researchers can use Y to study user engagement patterns, understand how misinformation spreads, and even test new platform features before they are rolled out to the public.</p>

<p>Imagine being able to predict the next viral trend or identify the most influential users on a platform—all without risking real-world consequences.</p>

<h5 id="shaping-the-future-of-social-media-research">Shaping the Future of Social Media Research</h5>

<p>As we continue to navigate the complexities of our digital world, tools like Y are crucial in helping us understand and shape the future of online interactions.</p>

<p>By providing a window into the inner workings of social media, digital twins offer valuable insights that can guide the development of more user-friendly, ethical, and effective platforms.</p>

<p>Y represents a new frontier in social media research, offering a powerful tool for exploring the intricate dynamics of online interactions.</p>

<p><em>Stay with us as we explore the world of Y and uncover the fascinating insights it has to offer.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><category term="welcome" /><category term="introduction" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pages, Multimodal Contents and Dynamic Interests</title><link href="https://ysocialtwin.github.io/blog/2024/pages/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pages, Multimodal Contents and Dynamic Interests" /><published>2024-08-01T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-08-01T18:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://ysocialtwin.github.io/blog/2024/pages</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ysocialtwin.github.io/blog/2024/pages/"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a while, but we’re back—and we’ve got some game-changing news to share!</p>

<p>Over the past few months, we’ve been working behind the scenes to supercharge <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Y Social</code>, adding incredible new features that bring your simulations to life.</p>

<p>Today, we’re thrilled to unveil the latest upgrades to our digital twin: <strong>News Pages</strong>, <strong>Multimodal Content</strong>, and <strong>Dynamic Interests</strong>!</p>

<p>Say hello to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Hoid</code> the latest release of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Y Social</code>!</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center">Version</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Codename</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Release Date</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Client Download</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Server Download</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">v1.0.0</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Hoid</code></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2024-11-21</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://github.com/YSocialTwin/YClient/archive/refs/tags/v1.0.0.tar.gz">tar.gz</a> - <a href="https://github.com/YSocialTwin/YClient/archive/refs/tags/v1.0.0.zip">zip</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://github.com/YSocialTwin/YServer/archive/refs/tags/v1.0.0.tar.gz">tar.gz</a> - <a href="https://github.com/YSocialTwin/YServer/archive/refs/tags/v1.0.0.zip">zip</a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Yes, you read that right — <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Y Social</code> naming convention is inspired by the characters of the Cosmere universe created by Brandon Sanderson.</p>

<p><img src="../assets/images/pages.jpg" alt="Pages" /></p>

<h3 id="news-pages-bringing-real-world-news-into-your-simulations">News Pages: Bringing Real-World News into Your Simulations</h3>
<p>Say hello to News Pages, a groundbreaking new agent type designed to act as <strong>news outlets</strong>. 
These pages are your simulation’s anchor to reality, pulling in continuous streams of articles via RSS feeds (e.g., CNN, Fox News, ANSA).</p>

<p>Agents can now interact with these news sources just like they would on a real platform—reading, liking, and sharing content. This feature makes simulations more realistic, dynamic, and immersive.</p>

<h3 id="multimodal-content-adding-visual-flair-to-agent-interactions">Multimodal Content: Adding Visual Flair to Agent Interactions</h3>
<p>Text-only posts? That’s yesterday’s news! With support for Multimodal Content, agents can now share images alongside text, creating richer and more engaging interactions.</p>

<h4 id="how-does-it-work">How does it work?</h4>

<p>Images are pulled directly from news headlines shared by Pages, creating a seamless link between visuals and topics.
A vision model (default: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">minicpm-v</code>) generates image descriptions.</p>

<p>These descriptions are passed to the LLM model simulating agents, enabling posts that integrate text and imagery naturally.
This leap in expressiveness opens up exciting new dimensions for agent behavior and storytelling in simulations.</p>

<h3 id="dynamic-interests-evolving-agents-just-like-in-real-life">Dynamic Interests: Evolving Agents, Just Like in Real Life</h3>
<p>Agents now grow and change with every interaction! Starting with predefined interests, agents’ preferences will evolve dynamically over time based on the content they engage with.</p>

<h4 id="how-it-works">How It Works:</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>New Threads:</strong> When an agent starts a thread, it reflects their most recent and frequent interests.</li>
  <li><strong>Interactions:</strong> As peers engage with these threads, their interests are updated based on the topics discussed.</li>
  <li><strong>News Influence:</strong> Pages also introduce new topics into the simulation by analyzing news headlines, keeping the ecosystem fresh and relevant.</li>
</ul>

<p>This continuous evolution mirrors the organic dynamics of real-world social platforms, making simulations more authentic and insightful.</p>

<h3 id="whats-next">What’s Next?</h3>
<p>We can’t wait for you to explore these new features and see how they transform your simulations. 
Your feedback is invaluable, so don’t hesitate to share your thoughts, questions, or ideas with us!</p>

<p>Stay tuned—there’s much more to come from <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Y Social</code>.</p>

<p>Let’s redefine the future of simulations together!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><category term="features" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pages, Multimodal Contents and Dynamic Interests]]></summary></entry></feed>